<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Timeline]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-03T07:06:49+11:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Anthony Kong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[find out script location in bash]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/03/03/find-out-script-location-in-bash/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-03T06:46:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/03/03/find-out-script-location-in-bash</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is the most portable method:</p>

<pre><code>  DIR="$( cd "$( dirname "${BASH_SOURCE[0]}" )" &amp;&amp; pwd )"
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[to quickly test a hipchat api token]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/03/02/to-quickly-test-a-hipchat-api-token/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-02T20:44:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/03/02/to-quickly-test-a-hipchat-api-token</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Try this</p>

<pre><code>curl https://api.hipchat.com/v2/room?auth_token=&lt;TOKEN&gt;
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to identify and kill process spawned by a tmux session?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/03/02/how-to-identify-and-kill-session/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-02T19:49:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/03/02/how-to-identify-and-kill-session</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An app is not responding in one of the pane of my tmux session. It does not respond to any Ctl-C and I forgot what the process is it.</p>

<p>So I did the following to identify the process:</p>

<pre><code>    $ tmux list-panes -s -F "#{pane_pid} #{pane_current_command}"
    1896 tmux
    1899 ssh
    $ pstree 1899  # Problem at the lower pane
    -+= 01899 antkong -zsh
     \--= 65662 antkong ssh -i prod.pem ubuntu@localhost -p 2222
</code></pre>

<p>Then run <code>kill -9 1899</code> to kill it</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lesson from learning to use vagrant, chef and sensu]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/03/02/lesson-from-vagrant/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-02T09:16:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/03/02/lesson-from-vagrant</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Couple of weeks ago I set out to learn to use vagrant + <strong>chef</strong> + sensu to achieve the goal of automated data server deployment and server monitoring.</p>

<p>I would like to share my experience so new comers can get up to speed faster and avoid some time-wasters.</p>

<p>The structure of this post can be confusing because it is more like my cliff note.</p>

<h2>Background of my final chioces</h2>

<p>A small startup that uses aws ec2 for key functionality. The tools should cost as little as possible. Open source solution is prefered.</p>

<h2>What are the advantages of vagrant, chef and sensu?</h2>

<p><strong>Vagrant</strong> and <strong>chef</strong> are great tools. They are indispensable to automation of VM creation and provision.</p>

<p><strong>Sensu</strong> is an open source monitoring platform. It is very flexible because it uses ruby to develop plugins to extend the framework&rsquo;s capability.</p>

<p>All of them have strong momentum from their communities</p>

<h2>Learning Vagrant</h2>

<h3>Vagrantfile</h3>

<p><strong>Vagrant</strong> is actually rather easy to master. The key file <strong>Vagrantfile</strong> is by itself a ruby script. It allows a lot of flexibility of customisation. The key hurdle is to write up a <strong>Vagrantfile</strong> that suits your need. The default <strong>Vagrantfile</strong> is pretty useless.</p>

<h3>Know your override</h3>

<p>You will need to know how to use the <code>override</code> object to customise your vagrant settings</p>

<h3>Provider</h3>

<p>A limitation of vagrant as of 1.6.x is that you can only use one active provider at a time. It means that if you have <code>vagrant up</code> to Virtualbox, you cannot fire up another instance in aws in the same folder. You can remove the &lsquo;.vagrant&rsquo; folder if you must.</p>

<h3>Provisioner</h3>

<p>My choice of provisioner is <strong>chef</strong>. I choose it over <strong>puppet</strong> mainly because of <strong>chef</strong> uses ruby as the scripting lanagage. <code>Nagios</code> is bascailly out of the question due to its legacy and complexity. Unfortunately there was a lot of changes at <strong>chef</strong> in last couple of months and it makes the learning experience less than pleasant. More on <strong>chef</strong> later.</p>

<h3>Plugins</h3>

<p>If your primary platform is aws, you will need to install <code>vagrant-aws</code>. There are a lot of useful plugins and it is something one should explore to discover all sort of possibility.</p>

<p>You will also need <code>vagrant-chef-zero</code>, <code>vagrant-omnibus</code> and <code>vagrant-berkshelf</code> in order to work with chef.</p>

<h2>Learning Chef</h2>

<h3>Implementation</h3>

<p>My goal is to make my <strong>chef</strong> cookbook and deployment as self-contained as possible.</p>

<h3>Lack of good documentation and Conflicting opinions abound</h3>

<p>I were unable to find a single starting point and clear documentation to learn <strong>chef</strong> on the official website. The documentation are either very fragmented or not up to date. The biggest distraction is the use of <strong>knife</strong>. It is tightly coupled with <strong>chef</strong> server. However in my opinion the power of <strong>chef</strong> actually lies with the concept of <code>cookbook</code>.</p>

<p>Apparently <strong>chef</strong> has released a number of tools before to help with devops&#8217; jobs.</p>

<p>The main tool, <strong>knife</strong>, confuses me because</p>

<ol>
<li><p>I want to run <strong>chef</strong> in a standalone mode and knife assumes you are using chef server</p></li>
<li><p>Some function like data bag creation is not useful</p></li>
</ol>


<p><strong>Librarian</strong> is superceded by <strong>berkshelf</strong>. Especially if you are going to use vagrant with chef, the brekshelf will take care of all the cookbook dependency automagically. Don&rsquo;t bother with <strong>libraian</strong>.</p>

<p>I think the book &ldquo;Learning Chef&rdquo; by Mischa Taylor is by far the most systemic and easy to read book in the subject area. If I have discovered this book at the begining I am sure I will save at least a week time in research.</p>

<h3>Confusing terminology</h3>

<p><a href="https://docs.chef.io/lwrp.html">LWRP</a> What the heck is it?</p>

<p>The document makes sense after I have used LWRP. However the document, like many other chef document, cannot give you a context or a big picture.</p>

<h3>Confusing branding</h3>

<p>Maybe I start at the wrong time? Last couple of months <strong>chef</strong> has been changing their urls. e.g. getchef.com becomes chef.io</p>

<p>And recipe respository is here: <a href="https://supermarket.chef.io">https://supermarket.chef.io</a>  and it is not linked from chef&rsquo;s main website.</p>

<p>Then they are also changing their github repository from <code>opcodes</code> to <code>chef</code></p>

<p>Utterly confusing to anyone who just started during this period.</p>

<h3>How to approach cookbook?</h3>

<p>I think cookbook is the best feature of chef, but it is not very adequately explained.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s why you need to get your hand dirty and learn how to write your cookbook by using <strong>kitchen</strong></p>

<p>At the beginning I thought I can get away from writing custom cookbook. I now see it as an impossibility.</p>

<h3>Keep converge until you get it</h3>

<p>Use <strong>kitchen</strong> to create a cookbook skeleton. Start write up your recipes.</p>

<p><strong>Tip</strong>: Break down your provisioning requirement into logical units and make them as self-contained and small and possible. In this way, you can test each individual recipe quickly with <code>kitchen converge</code>.</p>

<p>When you are happy with all the recipes, do the final integration test by running up the chef provision with <strong>vagrant</strong>.</p>

<h3>Sensu</h3>

<p>More on sensu later&hellip; To be continued</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[how to get sensu hipchat plugin to work]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/28/how-to-get-sensu-hipchat-plugin-to-work/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-28T18:55:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/28/how-to-get-sensu-hipchat-plugin-to-work</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I encountered two issues when I want to deploy the hipchat notification handler.</p>

<p>Firstly it throws an exception of &lsquo;Connection refused&rsquo;. But api.hipchat.com is reachable. I have verified by running <code>curl</code> against the v2 api.</p>

<pre><code>    $ cat /tmp/t.json |sudo /opt/sensu/embedded/bin/ruby  /etc/sensu/handlers/notification/hipchat.rb -j /etc/sensu
    /handlers/notification/hipchat.json
    /opt/sensu/embedded/lib/ruby/2.0.0/net/http.rb:878:in `initialize': Connection refused - connect(2) (Errno::ECONNREFUSED)
            from /opt/sensu/embedded/lib/ruby/2.0.0/net/http.rb:878:in `open'
            from /opt/sensu/embedded/lib/ruby/2.0.0/net/http.rb:878:in `block in connect'
            from /opt/sensu/embedded/lib/ruby/2.0.0/timeout.rb:52:in `timeout'
            from /opt/sensu/embedded/lib/ruby/2.0.0/net/http.rb:877:in `connect'
            from /opt/sensu/embedded/lib/ruby/2.0.0/net/http.rb:862:in `do_start'
            from /opt/sensu/embedded/lib/ruby/2.0.0/net/http.rb:851:in `start'
            from /opt/sensu/embedded/lib/ruby/2.0.0/net/http.rb:1367:in `request'
            from /opt/sensu/embedded/lib/ruby/gems/2.0.0/gems/sensu-plugin-1.1.0/lib/sensu-handler.rb:85:in `api_request'
            from /opt/sensu/embedded/lib/ruby/gems/2.0.0/gems/sensu-plugin-1.1.0/lib/sensu-handler.rb:120:in `stash_exists?'
            from /opt/sensu/embedded/lib/ruby/gems/2.0.0/gems/sensu-plugin-1.1.0/lib/sensu-handler.rb:132:in `block (2 levels) in filter_silenced'
            from /opt/sensu/embedded/lib/ruby/2.0.0/timeout.rb:66:in `timeout'
            from /opt/sensu/embedded/lib/ruby/2.0.0/timeout.rb:97:in `timeout'
</code></pre>

<p>It turns out all sensu plugin has a dependeny on the sensu api. I did not start the sensu api when I tested, and hence the exception.</p>

<p>Then I got a json config file related problem:</p>

<pre><code>    $ cat /tmp/t.json |sudo /opt/sensu/embedded/bin/ruby  /etc/sensu/handlers/notification/hipchat.rb -j /handlers/notification/hipchat.json
    /etc/sensu/handlers/notification/hipchat.rb:44:in `handle': undefined method `[]' for nil:NilClass (NoMethodError)
            from /opt/sensu/embedded/lib/ruby/gems/2.0.0/gems/sensu-plugin-1.1.0/lib/sensu-handler.rb:55:in `block in &lt;class:Handler&gt;'
</code></pre>

<p><code>-j</code> does not work as I expected. The script actually expects the .json configuration in the /opt/sensu/conf.d</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[sudo and glob]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/28/sudo-and-glob/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-28T16:52:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/28/sudo-and-glob</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Files are there but I cannot delete them</p>

<pre><code>    $ sudo ls /etc/sensu/conf.d/handlers
    email.json  handler.json  hipchat.json

    $ sudo rm /etc/sensu/conf.d/handlers/*.json
    rm: cannot remove ‘/etc/sensu/conf.d/handlers/*.json’: No such file or directory
</code></pre>

<p>It is because my current login has no permission to read <code>/etc/sensu/conf.d/handlers</code> and so glob failed</p>

<p>This takes care of the problem:</p>

<pre><code>    $ sudo bash -c 'rm /etc/sensu/conf.d/handlers/*.json'
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using chef sudo cookbook]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/27/using-chef-sudo-cookbook/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-27T12:53:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/27/using-chef-sudo-cookbook</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you want to LWRP to define a sudo user, do not use</p>

<pre><code>   include_recipe 'sudo'
</code></pre>

<p>It will blow away your default <code>/etc/sudoers</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Toastmaster speech 4]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/27/toastmaster-speech-4/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-27T07:06:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/27/toastmaster-speech-4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Feedback</h2>

<ul>
<li><p>The transition from introduction to first point can be done better</p></li>
<li><p>Hand clapping</p></li>
<li><p>Use of Jargon such as &lsquo;proxy&rsquo;</p></li>
<li><p>Repeated use of the word <code>Innovation</code></p></li>
<li><p>Subtitle can be improved</p></li>
</ul>


<h2>Self accessment</h2>

<p>Original version of the speech lasts almost 8 min. The final delivery time around 6m10s. A bit too fast.</p>

<p>I haven&rsquo;t been too successfully to use metaphors and vivid images in the speech. There is still use of jargon.</p>

<h1>Innovation</h1>

<p>Innovation has never got so much attention before. Innovation is a key driver of wealth creation. You probably already have an example of it in your pocket right now. Yes, nothing can highlight the impact of innovations better than Apple’s iPhone.</p>

<p>The success of iPhone actually combines several innovations in different area. They include supplier chain management, logistic, retails, brand management and product design.</p>

<p>So what it takes to be innovative? What can we do to come up with an truly innovative product? If you want to start the next Apple, the next Google or the next Tesla, You want to listen to these research results.</p>

<p>Size matters</p>

<p>Big corporate is not an ideal institute for innovation. Who would have thought? It is not so much a failure of the corporate because it is exactly what a corporate is designed for: avoid mistake! A big corporate has a series of command in place because new idea or product must be cross-examined and studied before they will receive a green light. They will do numerous marketing researches to decide if a product idea is viable.</p>

<p>When a product has to go through so many focus groups and polling, it is usually hardly innovative anymore. As Henry Ford has once put it famously: If you ask what a customer want out of a car, they will tell you a faster carriage!</p>

<p>That’s why over past decades, R&amp;D effort of giant like AT&amp;T, Xerox or IBM has little to show for as commercial products. Don’t get me wrong, their lab has produced brilliant ideas that change the world. For example Apple and Windows’ Graphical User Interface and Mouse is essentially a Xerox’s invention. But as an organisation, Xerox failed to capitalise the idea.</p>

<p>2) Gender matters</p>

<p>In another research, the researchers want to find out what makes a team great, or as they call it the Collective Intelligence. In two studies with about 700 people, working in groups of two to five, the researchers founds some factors that explains a group’s performance on a wide variety of tasks. This collective intelligence is not strongly correlated with the average or maximum individual intelligence of group members but is correlated with the average social sensitivity of group members and the equality in distribution of conversational turn-taking. And they are usually correlated to the proportion of females in the group.</p>

<p>In the tech startup world, teams are made up of usually predominantly socially awkward males (like me Exhibit A). Actually time and time again females have proven they are as competent if not better than their counterparts in engineering and computer science. If you are starting a new tech startup you should seriously rethink the prevailing bias against hiring females technical staff.</p>

<p>3) The mix matters</p>

<p>Have you thought about what a broadway musical successful? Is it the script or the score? Is it the genre? Is it the actors and actress? Or beautiful set and costume? After looking into how a company is formed, researchers find that actually it has a lot to do with the connections between the members: For a successful company, there is usually a healthy mix of, on the one hand, experienced veterans who have known and worked with each other for a long time, and on the other hand, relatively young and new members. Once this factor is identified, it just makes a lot of sense: The old and existing networks provides stability and experience to the team when the new kids on block comes and offer fresh angles and new inspiration. If the balance tilt either way, you will have either a company that may keep repeating its past success or a team of rookies who are struggling to get the basic right.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[gem install hipchat problem 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/27/hipchat-gem/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-27T05:41:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/27/hipchat-gem</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Error message:</p>

<pre><code>   [2015-02-26T11:49:52+00:00] ERROR: gem_package[hipchat] (zeetings::sensu_resource line 27) had an error: Mixlib::ShellOut::ShellCommandFailed: Expected process to exit with [0], but received '2'
   ---- Begin output of /opt/sensu/embedded/bin/gem install hipchat -q --no-rdoc --no-ri -v "1.4.0" ----
   STDOUT: 
   STDERR: ERROR:  Could not find a valid gem 'hipchat' (= 1.4.0), here is why:
      Unable to download data from https://rubygems.org/ - no such name (https://rubygems.org/quick/Marshal.4.8/hipchat-1.4.0.gemspec.rz)
   ERROR:  Possible alternatives: hipchat
   ---- End output of /opt/sensu/embedded/bin/gem install hipchat -q --no-rdoc --no-ri -v "1.4.0" ----
   Ran /opt/sensu/embedded/bin/gem install hipchat -q --no-rdoc --no-ri -v "1.4.0" returned 2
   [2015-02-26T11:49:52+00:00] FATAL: Chef::Exceptions::ChildConvergeError: Chef run process exited unsuccessfully (exit code 1)
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[gem install hipchat problem]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/26/gem-install-hipchat/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-26T22:45:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/26/gem-install-hipchat</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<pre><code>    Fetching: json-1.8.2.gem (100%)
    Building native extensions.  This could take a while...
    ERROR:  Error installing hipchat:
            ERROR: Failed to build gem native extension.

        /opt/sensu/embedded/bin/ruby extconf.rb
    creating Makefile

    make "DESTDIR="
    compiling generator.c
    make: gcc: Command not found
    make: *** [generator.o] Error 127


    Gem files will remain installed in /opt/sensu/embedded/lib/ruby/gems/2.0.0/gems/json-1.8.2 for inspection.
    Results logged to /opt/sensu/embedded/lib/ruby/gems/2.0.0/gems/json-1.8.2/ext/json/ext/generator/gem_make.out
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[cannot remove file]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/26/cannot-remove-file/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-26T21:36:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/26/cannot-remove-file</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Why I cannot remove this file redis_output.rb?</p>

<pre><code>    ~/d/z/a/v/c/z/f/d/s/e/handlers git:1685/setup-sensu-server-via-vagrant ❯❯❯ ls -l                                                                      ✭ ✖ ✱ ◼
    total 56
    -rwxr-xr-x  1 antkong  staff   2858 25 Feb 10:40 flapjack.rb
    -rwxr-xr-x  1 antkong  staff  11068 25 Feb 10:40 hipchat.rb
    -rw-r--r--  1 antkong  staff    941 25 Feb 10:40 redis_output.rb
    -rwxr-xr-x  1 antkong  staff   4594 25 Feb 10:40 ttl.rb
    ~/d/z/a/v/c/z/f/d/s/e/handlers git:1685/setup-sensu-server-via-vagrant ❯❯❯ git rm redis_output.rb                                                   ⏎ ✭ ✖ ✱ ◼
    fatal: pathspec 'redis_output.rb' did not match any files

    fatal: pathspec 'redis_output.rb' did not match any files
    ~/d/z/a/v/c/z/f/d/s/e/handlers git:1685/setup-sensu-server-via-vagrant ❯❯❯ git rm redis*.rb                                                         ⏎ ✭ ✖ ✱ ◼
    fatal: pathspec 'redis_output.rb' did not match any files
</code></pre>

<p>It is because I made a wrong assumpiton: the file is not under source control yet.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[installing sensu client 0.14 and 0.17.beta1]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/26/installing-sensu-client-0-dot-14-and-0-dot-17-dot-beta1/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-26T15:09:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/26/installing-sensu-client-0-dot-14-and-0-dot-17-dot-beta1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>0.17.beta1 does work for me. Fall back to 0.14 but the sensu client window service stopped working too.</p>

<p>I think the windows service needs to be re-registered. Very troublesome</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some useful apt and dpkg command]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/26/some-useful-apt-and-dpkg-command/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-26T09:59:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/26/some-useful-apt-and-dpkg-command</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>List all installed packages:</p>

<pre><code>dpkg --get-selection
</code></pre>

<p>List files coming from a package</p>

<pre><code>dpkg -L sensu
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to add apt mulitverse in chef]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/26/how-to-add-mulitverse-in-chef/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-26T03:27:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/26/how-to-add-mulitverse-in-chef</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Use &lsquo;ubuntu&rsquo; recipe</p>

<p>It is the output <code>sources.list</code></p>

<pre><code>    $ cat /etc/apt/sources.list
    #
    # Ubuntu trusty - Generated by Chef
    #

    deb http://us.archive.ubuntu.com/ubuntu trusty main restricted universe multiverse
    deb-src http://us.archive.ubuntu.com/ubuntu trusty main restricted universe multiverse

    deb http://us.archive.ubuntu.com/ubuntu trusty-updates main restricted universe multiverse
    deb-src http://us.archive.ubuntu.com/ubuntu trusty-updates main restricted universe multiverse

    #
    # Security updates
    #
    deb http://security.ubuntu.com/ubuntu trusty-security main restricted universe multiverse
    deb-src http://security.ubuntu.com/ubuntu trusty-security main restricted universe multiverse
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[sensu plugin problem]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/26/sensu-plugin-problem/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-26T02:12:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/26/sensu-plugin-problem</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Encountered problem when installing sensu-plugin</p>

<pre><code>    $ gem install sensu-plugin --no-rdoc --no-ri
    /usr/bin/ruby1.9.1 extconf.rb
    /usr/lib/ruby/1.9.1/rubygems/custom_require.rb:36:in `require': cannot load such file -- mkmf (LoadError)
            from /usr/lib/ruby/1.9.1/rubygems/custom_require.rb:36:in `require'
            from extconf.rb:1:in `&lt;main&gt;'
</code></pre>

<p>This is the solution: use the ruby runtime embedded in sensu</p>

<pre><code>    $ /opt/sensu/embedded/bin/gem install sensu-plugin
    Fetching: sensu-plugin-1.1.0.gem (100%)
    ERROR:  While executing gem ... (Gem::FilePermissionError)
        You don't have write permissions for the /opt/sensu/embedded/lib/ruby/gems/2.0.0 directory.
    vagrant@default-ubuntu-1404:~$ sudo /opt/sensu/embedded/bin/gem install sensu-plugin
    Successfully installed sensu-plugin-1.1.0
    Parsing documentation for sensu-plugin-1.1.0
    Installing ri documentation for sensu-plugin-1.1.0
    1 gem installed
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[knife did not create any data bag]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/25/knife-did-not-create-any-data-bag/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-25T11:36:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/25/knife-did-not-create-any-data-bag</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I want to create an offline cookbook. I want to create a user databag to use the <code>users</code> recipe. I ran</p>

<pre><code>knife data bag create users
</code></pre>

<p>but it created nothing in the databag folder.</p>

<p>It turns out I need to run it in local mode and give it a user name:</p>

<pre><code>knife data bag create users myuser -z
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[resize tmux window]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/25/resize-tmux-window/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-25T10:38:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/25/resize-tmux-window</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The size of the window is limited by the smallest size of attached client.</p>

<p>So to reset the size we need to detach all non-active clients</p>

<p>This is the command:</p>

<pre><code> C-b :attach -d
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[tmux resizing pane]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/25/tmux-resizing-pane/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-25T01:20:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/25/tmux-resizing-pane</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I want to increase a height of a pane in a tmux session. I tried &lsquo;C-b C-<Up>&rsquo;, but since my C-<UP> is binded to expose in OSX, it did not work.</p>

<p>Fortunately it is very easy to control the behavior via command line. First of all, you need to identify the pane. It can be done either by a &lsquo;C-b q&rsquo; or by command <code>tmux list-panes</code>. The pane from which you issued the command will be marked as <code>active</code>.</p>

<p>Once the id of the pane is identified, you can run the following command:</p>

<pre><code>   tmux resize-pane -t 1 -U    # 1 is the pane id 
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[useful vbox command]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/23/useful-vbox-command/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-23T21:21:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/23/useful-vbox-command</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This will list out all the VMs</p>

<pre><code>    $ VBoxManage list vms
    "virtualbox_default_1418633437021_83822" {0342b0ad-d64c-4864-a0e2-c16235dc6ff2}
    "serverr" {eca868d2-6d5d-4b49-b076-27f5ef396355}
    "sensu_client" {70b38f62-0a0c-4965-b4f4-5360ec761d64}
    "analytics" {ab9e59e4-7058-4c9f-80af-c403348cac6f}
    "sensu-server_default_1424653555631_75219" {4d7174f7-6f7b-4732-98c3-9509c426cae3}
    "simple-sensu-client_default_1424660131045_1714" {1eb59ae6-2d5e-4b0f-9135-a7de6c882e1d}
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Innovation]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/22/innovation/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-22T21:32:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/22/innovation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Video</h2>

<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Mtjatz9r-Vc">The art of innovation by Guy Kawasaki</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pii8tTx1UYM">Our approach to innovation is dead wrong by Diana Kander</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YKV3rhzvaC8">The New Rules of Innovation by Carl Bass</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iG9CE55wbtY">Do schools kill creativity? by Sir Ken Robinson</a></p>

<blockquote><p>(In a kids&#8217; nativity play) The three boys came in, four-year-olds with tea towels on their heads, and they put these boxes down, and the first boy said, &ldquo;I bring you gold.&rdquo; And the second boy said, &ldquo;I bring you myrrh.&rdquo; And the third boy said, &ldquo;Frank sent this.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Actually, do you know that old philosophical thing, if a tree falls in a forest and nobody hears it, did it happen? Remember that old chestnut? I saw a great t-shirt recently, which said, &ldquo;If a man speaks his mind in a forest, and no woman hears him, is he still wrong?&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p><a href="http://www.ted.com/talks/ken_robinson_says_schools_kill_creativity/transcript?language=en"><em>Full transcript</em></a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=86x-u-tz0MA">Your elusive creative genius by Elizabeth Gilbert</a></p>

<blockquote><p>Fear based questions</p></blockquote>

<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kIruNparMGQ">The Face of Innovation by JR Reagan</a></p>

<blockquote><p>Freshpaper</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
