<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: requests | Timeline]]></title>
  <link href="http://kongakong.github.io/blog/categories/requests/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kongakong.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-22T20:23:53+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://kongakong.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Anthony Kong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Whenever you think you need urllib2, you actually need requests]]></title>
    <link href="http://kongakong.github.io/blog/2013/05/14/p-50367270258/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-14T07:21:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://kongakong.github.io/blog/2013/05/14/p-50367270258</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Since I have started using python since version 2.4, I have a lot of old die-hard habit. For one, I write exception handler like this</p>

<p>instead  of</p>

<p>The later is of course a better and more flexible style.</p>

<p>So, today, when I want to write up a simple test to post data to a web server, I imported lib urllib2 right away.</p>

<p>It usually works great… unTIL you need something more than basic.</p>

<p>Apparently I need to set some cookie and set to the server. Let’s import cookiejar and cookie…</p>

<p>Why it throws an exception <em>AttributeError: ‘SimpleCookie’ object has no attribute +’rfc2965’</em>?</p>

<p>OK, let’s import DefaultCookiePolicy. Then I got hit by a <em>missing domain attribute</em> exception. “Do I need to use a lower level Cookie class to set the domain?”, I wonder. Try switching to Cookie and it throw this exception</p>

<p>At this point I said to myself: No, I am not going to figure out the 17 arguments. My test code is at this point in this dismal state:.</p>

<p>Instead of continuing banging my head against a wall, I recall reading about ‘requests’ module. Let give it a go.</p>

<p>Like magic, it is all I need. 2 lines.</p>

<p>It just works. Well done, requests!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
