<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: riak | Timeline]]></title>
  <link href="http://kongakong.github.io/post/categories/riak/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kongakong.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-03T09:10:00+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://kongakong.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Anthony Kong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Different Type of Database Models]]></title>
    <link href="http://kongakong.github.io/post/2013/07/29/different-type-of-database/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-29T08:08:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://kongakong.github.io/post/2013/07/29/different-type-of-database</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I find this summary in <a href="http://littleriakbook.com/">Eric Redmond&rsquo;s &lsquo;A Little Riak&rsquo;</a> book  very concise and useful.</p>

<ol>
<li><p><strong>Relational</strong> Traditional databases usually use SQL to model and query data. They are useful for data which can be stored in a highly structured schema, yet require lexible querying. Scaling a relational database (RDBMS) traditionally occurs by more powerful hardware (vertical growth).</p>

<p>Examples: PostgreSQL, MySQL, Oracle</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Graph</strong> These exist for dataighly interconnected data. They excel in modeling complex relationships between nodes, and many implementations can handle multiple billions of nodes and relationships (or edges and vertices). I tend to include triplestores and object DBs as specialized variants.</p>

<p> Examples: Neo4j, Graphbase, IniniteGraph</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Document</strong> Document datastores model hierarchical values called documents, represented in formats such as JSON or XML, and do not enforce a document schema. They generally support distributing across multiple servers (horizontal growth).</p>

<p> Examples: CouchDB, MongoDB, Couchbase</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Columnar</strong> Popularized by Google’s BigTable, this form of database exists to scale across mul- tiple servers, and groups similar data into column families. Column values can be individually versioned and managed, though families are deined in advance, not unlike RDBMS schemas.</p>

<p> Examples: HBase, Cassandra, BigTable 4</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Key/Value</strong> Key/Value, or KV stores, are conceptually like hashtables, where values are stored and accessed by an immutable key. They range from single-server varieties like Memcached used for high-speed caching, to multi-datacenter distributed systems like Riak Enterprise.</p>

<p> Examples: Riak, Redis, Voldemort</p></li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
