<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: finance | Timeline]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/categories/finance/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-10T13:37:49+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Anthony Kong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[yield to maturity]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2014/03/06/yield-to-maturity/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-06T07:13:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2014/03/06/yield-to-maturity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yield to maturity (YTM) is sometimes  known simply as “yield”, “redemption yield” or “gross redemption yield” (GRY) because it is the yield to the redemption date assuming all cashflows are paid gross (no tax deduction for example).</p>

<p>It is the internal rate of return of a bond – the yield necessary to discount all the bond’s cashflows to an NPV equal to its current price</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[bid-ask spread and swap spread]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2014/01/29/bid-ask-spread/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-29T08:11:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2014/01/29/bid-ask-spread</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For a 5-year swap, for example, a bank’s swap desk might quote the following:</p>

<pre><code>Floating-rate payer: pay 6-month LIBOR
receive a fixed rate of 5.19 percent

Fixed-rate payer: pay a fixed rate of 5.25 percent
receive 6-month LIBOR
</code></pre>

<p>In this example, the bank is quoting an offer rate of 5.25 percent, which is what the fixed-rate payer will pay, and a bid rate of 5.19 percent, which is what the floating-rate payer will receive. The bid-offer spread is therefore 6 basis points.</p>

<p>The fixed rate is always set at a spread over the government bond yield curve and is often quoted that way. Say the 5-year Treasury is trading at a yield of 4.88 percent. The 5-year swap bid and offer rates in the example are 31 basis points and 37 basis points, respectively, above this yield, and the bank’s swap trader could quote the swap rates as a swap spread: 37–31. This means that the bank would be willing to enter into a swap in which it paid 31 basis points above the benchmark yield and received LIBOR or one in which it received 37 basis points above the yield curve and paid LIBOR.</p>

<p>(Quoted from &lsquo;Fixed Income Securities and Derivatives Handbook Analysis and Valuation&rsquo; )</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[AFS]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2013/06/08/p-52451932662/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-08T20:40:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2013/06/08/p-52451932662</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Morgan Stanley uses <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Andrew_File_System">AFS</a> for application deployment with good results.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[When there is a positive correlation between the financing rate r and a future contract subjected to marks-to-market rules, the future  will be convex and will trade above the forwards of the same delivery]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2012/02/21/p-17967651732/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-21T08:19:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2012/02/21/p-17967651732</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When there is a positive correlation between the financing rate r and a future contract subjected to marks-to-market rules, the future  will be convex and will trade above the forwards of the same delivery</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The contamination principle dictates that every nonlinear security commands time value, positive if the security is convex and negative if it is concave.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2012/01/10/p-15582485815/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-10T08:43:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2012/01/10/p-15582485815</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The contamination principle dictates that every nonlinear security commands time value, positive if the security is convex and negative if it is concave.</p>

<p>Nassim Taleb, <em>Dynamic Hedging</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
