<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Zbigniew_Brzezinski | Timeline]]></title>
  <link href="http://kongakong.github.io/blog/categories/zbigniew-brzezinski/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kongakong.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-29T20:08:46+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://kongakong.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Anthony Kong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Grand Chessboard by Zbigniew Brzezinski (12)]]></title>
    <link href="http://kongakong.github.io/blog/2012/07/25/p-27974299342/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-25T19:40:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://kongakong.github.io/blog/2012/07/25/p-27974299342</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Finally reached the final chapter of the book.</p>

<blockquote><p><em>The point of departure for the needed [US] policy has to be hard-nosed recognition of the three unprecedented conditions that currently define the geopolitical state of world affairs: for the first time in history, (1) a single state is a truly global power, (2) a non-Eurasian state is globally the preeminent state, and (3) the globe’s central arena, Eurasia, is dominated by a non-Eurasian power.</em></p></blockquote>

<p>One of the interesting theme in this book is that it has an taken-for-granted conviction that USA <em>The Only Global Power on Earth</em> is a given. The author does not even try to explain why it should be the case.  The whole book is basically a guide or a blueprint of how to project American influence onto Eurasia, the most important landmass on Earth.</p>

<p>This book is still relevant today because it helps one to understand the underlying principle of USA’s foreign policy since the G. W. Bush/Neocon era. ( You probably can argue it is not entirely different from that before then)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Grand Chessboard by Zbigniew Brzezinski (11)]]></title>
    <link href="http://kongakong.github.io/blog/2012/07/24/p-27901418274/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-24T19:51:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://kongakong.github.io/blog/2012/07/24/p-27901418274</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While Chapter 6 in &lsquo;The Grand Chessboard&rsquo; (1997) by Zbigniew Brzezinski talks a lot about China, it actually talks a  lot more about Japan.</p>

<p>The author has a rather clear idea why Japan is isolated in the Asia region. The dilemma of Japan: if Japan tries to assert its regional leadership role to counter China, it will find itself surrounded by a hosTILe Russia, a distrusting Korea and South East Asia, and  a China that will play a rapid catch-up. Basically the only way forward, as seen by Zbigniew, is for Japan to leverage its alliance with America to gain influence on <em>International</em> stage.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Grand Chessboard by Zbigniew Brzezinski (10)]]></title>
    <link href="http://kongakong.github.io/blog/2012/07/23/p-27826866568/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-23T19:40:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://kongakong.github.io/blog/2012/07/23/p-27826866568</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Chapter 6, titled ‘The Far Eastern Anchor’, in &lsquo;The Grand Chessboard&rsquo;(1997) by Zbigniew Brzezinski is about Asia. In regard to China, Zbigniew said:</p>

<blockquote><p><em>Chinese consumption of energy is already expanding at a rate that far exceeds domestic production. That excess will widen in any case, but especially so if China’s rate of growth continues to be very high.</em></p></blockquote>

<p>I am always impressed by how well scholars or researchers in the Stats have done in the study of China. Remember the Economists have predicted cruel oil price would hit $5 a barrel in 1999? This was apparently a prediction based on extrapolation of the then oil price movement. But a geo-strategist sees beyond short-run trends and tries to foresee how nations will engage each others to compete for finite resource on planet Earth.</p>

<p>Actually reading this book now I realise a fair numbers of predictions made in this chapter are not too far off the mark, e.g.</p>

<p>1) energy and food supply issue</p>

<p>2) when China will surpass Japan’s GDP (<em>‘within two decades [from 1997]’</em>), and may rival that of USA</p>

<p>3) Tension between China and other Asian countries</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Grand Chessboard by Zbigniew Brzezinski (9)]]></title>
    <link href="http://kongakong.github.io/blog/2012/07/21/p-27690063634/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-21T19:58:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://kongakong.github.io/blog/2012/07/21/p-27690063634</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In chapter 5, ‘The Eurasian Balkans’, of &lsquo;The Grand Chessboard&rsquo; (1997) by Zbigniew Brzezinski, it covers the histories of Central Asia that was part of the former USSR. The three states of the Caucasus &ndash; Armenia, Georgia, and Azerbaijan &ndash; can be said to be based on truly historic nations. But the frontiers of five new Central Asian states were drawn arbitrarily by Soviet cartographers in the 1920s and 1930s. They are rich in resource but of relatively weak power. It invites Russia, Turkey and Iran to contest to fill the power vacuum.</p>

<p>Interestingly read because I know nothing about this part of the world.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Grand Chessboard by Zbigniew Brzezinski (8)]]></title>
    <link href="http://kongakong.github.io/blog/2012/07/19/p-27547164925/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-19T19:57:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://kongakong.github.io/blog/2012/07/19/p-27547164925</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In chapter 4 of &lsquo;The Grand Chessboard&rsquo; (1997), Zbigniew Brzezinski discusses the void of power in the former Soviet territory after the collapse of USSR. The material and analysis is very dated. For one, President Yeltsin was sTILl in power when this chapter is written. Current Russian administration bears little resemblance to Yeltsin’s government.</p>

<p>A lot of subjective wishes as to what Russian should do or not.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
