<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: story | Timeline]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/categories/story/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-04-16T09:55:12+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Anthony Kong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[cats and mice by Tommy Douglas]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/03/21/cats-and-mice/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-21T10:40:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/03/21/cats-and-mice</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>It’s the story of a place called Mouseland. Mouseland was a place where all the little mice lived and played, were born and died. And they lived much the same as you and I do.They even had a Parliament. And every four years they had an election. Used to walk to the polls and cast their ballots. Some of them even got a ride to the polls. And got a ride for the next four years afterwards too. Just like you and me. And every time on election day all the little mice used to go to the ballot box and they used to elect a government. A government made up of big, fat, black cats.</p>

<p>Now if you think it strange that mice should elect a government made up of cats, you just look at the history of Canada for last 90 years and maybe you’ll see that they weren’t any stupider than we are. Now I’m not saying anything against the cats&hellip; They passed good laws -– that is, laws that were good for cats. But the laws that were good for cats weren’t very good for mice&hellip; They voted the black cats out. They put in the white cats. Now the white cats had put up a terrific campaign. They said: &ldquo;All that Mouseland needs is more vision.&rdquo; They said:&ldquo;The trouble with Mouseland is those round mouseholes we got. If you put us in we’ll establish square mouseholes.&rdquo; And they did. And the square mouseholes were twice as big as the round mouseholes, and now the cat could get both his paws in. And life was tougher than ever&hellip; Presently there came along one little mouse who had an idea. My friends, watch out for the little fellow with an idea. And he said to the other mice, &ldquo;Look fellows, why do we keep on electing a government made up of cats? Why don’t we elect a government made up of mice?&rdquo; &ldquo;Oh,&rdquo; they said, &ldquo;he’s a Bolshevik. Lock him up!&rdquo; So they put him in jail.</p>

<p>But I want to remind you: that you can lock up a mouse or a man but you can’t lock up an idea.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
