<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: idea | Timeline]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/categories/idea/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-03T23:01:18+11:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Anthony Kong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It is a very old news, back in 2004:]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2012/06/28/p-26063045790/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-28T19:34:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2012/06/28/p-26063045790</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It is a very old news, back in 2004:</p>

<p>“Three gamblers who won Â£1.3m at the Ritz Club casino using technology worthy of James Bond have been allowed to keep their winnings. The three peopleâdescribed as a âchic and beautifulâ Hungarian woman and two âelegantâ Serbian menâwere accused of using a laser scanner hidden inside a mobile phone to measure the speed of the ball on the roulette table at the St James club. This beamed the data to a microcomputer, which predicted where it would land, flashing the information on the phone’s screen. The trio was arrested in March.</p>

<p>London’s police have not said whether they found such a device. But on December 7th they announced that no further action would be taken and that their inquiry was over. The three suspects, who were on bail, are now free to leave Britain. The Times newspaper reported that because the high-tech scanner didn’t interfere with the ball or roulette wheel, the gamblers had not broken the law.”</p>

<p>It will not be hard to implement in Android or iOS these days, I suppose? :&ndash;)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A fun idea]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2011/04/18/p-4711913957/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-18T15:24:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2011/04/18/p-4711913957</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A fun idea: why not do something to drive objective-c runtime system using erlang?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Java vs Python (Prolog)]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2011/04/02/p-6106984922/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-02T23:44:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2011/04/02/p-6106984922</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you are expecting some sort of combative comments in this post, you will be disappointed.</p>

<p>It all started a few days ago: I was asked by someone of extensive Java development background about the advantage of python, and if it is a suitable language for large scale. Despite I have been doing python application (web app) development for a few years, I found that my arguments did not come off very convincing.</p>

<p>So it gives me an idea to write a few, hopefully useful, pieces on this subject matter.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
