<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: toastmaster | Timeline]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/categories/toastmaster/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-21T16:22:19+11:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Anthony Kong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My toastmaster speech 3]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/21/my-toastmaster-speech-3/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-21T11:25:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/21/my-toastmaster-speech-3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Remark</h1>

<p>The original cut (as shown in following) is considerably longer than what I have delivered finally. It is because, after timing myself, the text takes about 8 min to finish. So I have trimmed off part of the speech. The paradox: when I finally delivered it in front of the audience, it took 9 seconds short of 6 minutes. I have talked a lot faster during the speech.</p>

<h1>Feedback</h1>

<ul>
<li><p>Vocal variation</p></li>
<li><p>The opening can be better</p></li>
<li><p>What I have done right: the speech provided a vivid imagery.</p></li>
</ul>


<h1>Text</h1>

<p>Memory. I want to talk to you about memory today.</p>

<p>How good is your memory? Do you want a little challenge? I will give you a list of random items. let’s see if you can remember them all?
I have watched a seminar by an American World Memory Championship champion Chester Santos just a month ago. I would love to share his insight and tip with you.</p>

<p>But before I continue, let’s me give you a little challenge. Let me give a list of random words and see if you can remember it. OK? Here it is:</p>

<p>Monkey, Iron, Rope, Kite, House, Paper, Shoe, Worm, Envelope, Pencil, River, Rock, Tree, Coin</p>

<p>Did you get them all? Do you think you can recite the list both forward and backward? I will tell you how later in the talk.</p>

<p>But first let me tell you about some common misunderstandings about memory.</p>

<p>The first common one is: our memory get worse when we get older. It is easy to understand why we have this misconception. When we were young and studying in schools, we have to remember tons of information and get quizzed from time to time. After we leave school and get our first job, we again need to absorb massive amount of new information in order to do our job well. However it is typical that in later stage of our lives, when we settle into our roles, we do not need to learn and recall the same amount of new information anymore. Since we do not use our brain for memorisation, its ability to retain and recall data becomes worse. It is just like any muscle system in our body: lack of exercise will make them weak. But we usually draw a wrong conclusion: we think our memory deteriorated because we are getting old. It is simply not true. It is more a result of our life style. As a good counter example, in a World Memory Championship some years ago, there was a contestant from Malaysia who is in his 60s. Despite his age, he managed to remember all entries in an oxford dictionary AND the words position on a page AND the associated page numbers.</p>

<p>Another misunderstanding is: it takes a special brain to memorise massive amount of data. Actually use of appropriate memory techniques will go a long way. Every one of us can master the techniques.</p>

<p>We have actually a lot of untapped memory capacity such as visual and olfactory memory. Visual memory is extremely powerful: for example, we can remember faces we have come across years ago. If we can enlist the visual memory, we can store a lot of information in our brain. The key is that the images have to be exaggerated, crazy and unusual.</p>

<p>[Take 3 4min mark] It is very easy to understand why: let’s say now, out of nowhere, a big pink elephant break through those wall (points to far end), run across this room and then break this wall (points behind me) and escaped. I am sure 30 years from now, all of us will still recall every details of the episode and cannot stop talking about it.</p>

<p>Do you still remember the list I throw at you at the beginning of this speech? It is actually an example used by the World Memory Championship Champion Chester Santos in his demonstration. So let do this  visual memory exercise together!</p>

<p>First imagine a monkey who is happily running around and making some monkey sound. For some reason it finds a giant iron and he starts to dance around with the iron in his hand. On one end of iron it is attached to a rope. You can feel the rope and it feels rough. You look up the rope and you can see it is attached to a kite. Somehow the kite starts to fall and hit a house. The house is very special and is all covered by paper. Out of nowhere a  shoe appears and it walks on the papers and leave footprints all over the place.</p>

<p>Then you notice there is a worm in the shoe. Try picture this. You want to take a closer look but the worn jumps out and get inside an envelope. Now a pencil appears and write all over the envelope. The pencil then jumps into a river and makes a big splash. The river is crashing up a rock. Near the rock there is a tree. And there is cheese growing up on the tree. Coins are shooting out from the cheese.</p>

<p>Now you have a story. Now you have a picture. You can now easily recite the list of words: Monkey, Iron, Rope, Kite, House, Paper, Shoe, Worm, Envelope, Pencil, River, Rock, Tree, Coin. And you can go backward too. Do you try to it with me? Coin, Tree, Rock, River, Pencil, Envelope, Worm, Shoe, Paper, House, Kite, Rope, Iron, Monkey! Yes, you did it!</p>

<p>In conclusion: 1) Your memory does not get worse because you get old. It gets worse because you do not use it enough. 2) Our brain does not hold as much data as you wish because you do not know how to tape into your visual memory.</p>

<p>Thank You.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My attempt at toastmaster speech #2]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/01/13/toastmaster-speech-2/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-13T04:33:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/01/13/toastmaster-speech-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is my second speech and I find that writing a speech is not a easy task. First of all it takes time to think of a right topic. Then it takes a lot of practices and effort to be able to give the speech without note. It definitely motivated me to look at memorisation techniques.</p>

<h1>The Speech</h1>

<p>You are alone, in the dark. It is coming. It is getting closer. You can almost smell it. You are tired, you are exhausted. You are making a last ditch effort in last 12 hours non-stop. You are anxious because you are not sure if everything gonna turn out as planned. Your enemy is invisible yet its feels so real. I am talking about one of the worst enemies in our work lives: meeting the Deadline!</p>

<p>Does this feeling sound familiar to you? Raise your hand if you had this experience before!</p>

<p>Deadline is called deadline for good reasons. The time is set in stone. The consequence of failure is real. If your project misses the deadline, it could mean a failure to meet your customer expectation. Your organisation can suffer from reputational damage and some heads gonna roll! It could well be yours.</p>

<p>Can we tame this monster?</p>

<p>There is a few things you can do to make it easier to meet the deadlines</p>

<p>First of all, understand the objective of your project! It sounds obvious but it is extremely important.</p>

<p>Imagine you are an explorer and is lost in jungle. You want to get out of it alive. It really does not matter if you know how to clear a path with your machete or how to swing from tree to tree like Tarzan. But if you are heading the wrong direction you will never get out!</p>

<p>Sometimes we are too obsessed with operational details, we forget to ask the big picture question: What do we want to achieve? What is the expected outcome? How will we measure success or failure? These are the questions that we have to ask. These are the questions that set the direction.</p>

<p>Next. Planning. To plan well means we need to identify constraints and limitations we will face in a project.</p>

<p>A typical project has a lot of internal and external dependencies. These dependencies can become constraints and, in some case, even a blocker.</p>

<p>Here is a typical example of a constraint: The new system is dependent on the implementation of a new feature by an external vendor. The vendor does not have the capability to deliver this new feature in your timeframe. So our capability to deliver is constrained by how well the vendor can meet our deadline.</p>

<p>Sometimes a constraint can become a blocker. Say your project requires a key piece of new software which can only be run on an latest version of an operating system. But your internal IT insists that you can only use an older version because of policy.  How are you going to resolve it?</p>

<p>It is important to map out all the potential blockers on the critical path. The failure to do so can bring u unpleasant surprise.</p>

<p>3 Use milestones</p>

<p>Milestone is a technique to break a project down into smaller module. They are good checkpoints for monitoring the health of a project. Once you hit a milestone, it is a good time to pause and check if the original estimate is good, reexamine all the assumption, dependencies and constraints you have identified.</p>

<p>4 Set buffer.</p>

<p>What is buffer? Buffer basically means extra time and resources to prepare for the unexpected. Life is full of unexpected event. Your software vendor may suddenly goes of business; your key employee may become ill and cannot report to work for a while; A sudden change in market condition forces you make some last minute revision… All of these will add pressure on your already tight schedule. If you have not budgeted for these risks in a project, you will be likely end up in a position that you have to scramble to find extra resource and, more often than not, put extra pressure on an already stressed out team.</p>

<p>Burning midnight oil to meet deasline is not a fun experience. Keeping a good and even pace at work is key to avoid burnout. Therefore let me rehash the main points:</p>

<p>Understand the objective; know where you are going
Have a clear idea of the constraints and the limits &ndash; it can only done well if you understand your task or product well
Break a project into modules and assign milestones. Each milestone is a checkpoint to review the past performance and adjust the plan and direction.</p>

<p>With these technique you will be able to defeat this monster known as Deadline. After all we work to live, not live to work!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
