<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: toastmaster | Timeline]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/categories/toastmaster/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-26T07:11:47+11:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Anthony Kong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[toastmaster speech 5]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/03/24/toastmaster-speech-5/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-24T08:55:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/03/24/toastmaster-speech-5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Speech No. 5 &ndash; Getting Old</h2>

<p>The goal of the #5 speech is about using body language and gesture to tell a story. I suppose the best way to do it is to talk about something exciting and uplifting. Then I can wave my arms like this. Maybe I can  go around here truly excited. But somehow I want to set the a bar a bit higher. I want to do something different. I actually want to talk about boring, not-interesting. Something people don’t want to think too much about. Something rather depressing and sad.</p>

<p>Dear fellow toastmasters and guest, I would like to talk today is Getting Old.   Yes, G-e-t-t-i-n-g  O-l-d.</p>

<p>How many of you have looked forward to getting old when you are teenager? Exactly what I thought. None. When we are young, growing old is such an alien concept. To live like a 60 years old or older is simply beyond imagination.</p>

<p>But somehow, someone would like to remind you actually your biological clock is ticking.</p>

<p>This someone is none other than your passive aggressive … BODY!</p>

<p>I got my first notice not long ago: Hair is growing inside my ears! To me it is absolutely absurd for hair to grow inside my ears. What is point of having hair in the ears? I don’t even feel cold inside my ears! I will assert that hair has absolutely no business whatsoever inside the ears. That’s right. There I said it! [Wave fist] But somehow there they are. They are growing inside the ears. Then the hair in the nostril joins the party. Maybe somehow they don’t like the damp environment anymore. They start to grow longer and longer. Kind of feel like they want to retire and move to the sunshine coast and enjoy more sun.</p>

<p>The problem does not stop here. For the lucky ones gary hair starts to take over, “Snow on the roof” as you may call it. Not sure if they got snow in the basement too but I am not keen to find out.</p>

<p>I suppose to wink here but I think I gonna scare the ladies, since I am already on a rather uncomfortable, hairy subject here. I’ll probably look creepy.</p>

<p>For the unlucky ones, like me, the hair simply goes Missing in Action. The receding hair line is going backward like the French army in WWII. They are disappearing rapidly like the water in a water hole in a drought season. Looking myself in mirror I understand why hair growth industry is such a multi-billion dollar business. If nothing works, I can understand why to some combover is an option.</p>

<p>Of course, on a serious note, ageing is actually no a laughing matter. As a matter of fact, more and more resources are devoted to the study of ageing. I did a quick search on google scholar. Merely 30 years ago, there were roughly 50,000 medical papers on ageing. But in recent years, number of papers has grown to 200,000 ~ 250,000. The focus of research has changed as well. The focus has changed from longevity and life expectancy to more qualitative aspect of ageing such as quality of life. While modern medicine is capable of keeping us healthy for longer, degenerative disease like dementia can have huge impact on the patient and his/her carer. Another shift of focus is from addressing the symptom of ageing to deeper understanding of the mechanism of ageing. For example, the Sydney based biomedical researcher David Sinclair has made a breakthrough in the understanding of the ageing process at the DNA level. As we know, DNA controls the formation of cell by turning certain on and off. And depends on the gene expression we have different kind of cells like liver cell, skin cell and brain cell. Sinclair discovers that for human, our DNS is programmed to turn on all the genes when we ages. It causes damages to our gene. More importantly Sinclair discovered a molecules known as SIR2, which stands for Silent Information Regulator 2, that can turn off these genes that should not be turned on. Or in the other word, we can reverse the aging process!</p>

<p>Oh, wait a minute, there is a good news when talking about getting old after all! [Arm waving!]</p>

<p>In the end Aging is not just about your body, it is about you mind too. I would like share this saying about getting old with you: “You become old when all your dream and hope is replaced by regrets”</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Table Topic Master]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/03/12/table-topic-master/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-12T09:03:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/03/12/table-topic-master</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Table Topic</h2>

<p>Thanks Chair.</p>

<p>Dear fellow toastmasters and guest. Welcome to our table topic segment</p>

<p>Table Topic is about impromptu speaking. I will invite 8 of us to come forward and speak to us on the spot for 1 min, on topic I will reveal just before you’re picked.</p>

<p>The purpose of the table topic is to help us to develop our ability to organize our thoughts quickly and respond to an impromptu question or topic. That’s why we don’t want the Table Topic participant to just ramble for a minute, just saying one word after another.</p>

<p>In fact, a good table topic should appear well-organised. It should have an opening, a body and a conclusion.</p>

<p>You will have a minute of time to give your speech. The ember light will come on at 45sec. The red will come on at 1 minute. If you hit the one minute mark, I’d appreciate if you can wrap up immediately. It is because in a real TT contest, overtime will result in disqualification. We also want to keep the meeting time under control.</p>

<p>For the even number speakers we will have [XXX] as the evaluator. For the odd number speakers we will have [YYY] as the evaluator.</p>

<p>Without further ado, let’s start!</p>

<p>The theme of tonight’s Table Topic: What will you do if you receive an unexpected fortune? I will give you different scenario and let see how you will handle it.</p>

<p>Situation number one: You are one lucky Toastmaster. You stumbled upon a genie in a bottle and you have released it from years of confinement. He can grant you a wish, but you have to choose between one of these two choices: Stay young forever or have abundant wealth. How would you choose? [Stay young forever or have abundant wealth]</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Look like we have yet another lucky toastmaster. Another TM stumbled upon a genie in a bottle. Unfortunately this genie’s power is bit limited. You are given two choices again, but they are: to become a boss of a bottle shop or a car wash business. Which one would you choose? [Bottle shop or car wash?]</p></li>
<li><p>Looks like another toastmaster strikes it lucky too! Another genie in a bottle is found!  Again there are two things to choose from: You can have a beautiful voice like Susan Boyle that will let you make millions out of singing, but a face like the Orc from Lord of the ring; or you can have a good look like Emma [Mma] Watson or Brad Pitt that will let make millions out of acting, but a voice like an Orc from Lord of the Ring. How would you choose? [Beautiful voice or beautiful face]</p></li>
<li><p>You will not believe the luck of this club! One more fellow Toastmaster find a genie in a bottle! But oh no, it is the small business genie again. Now you have a choice between a fish and chip shop and a pizza restaurant. Which one will you choose and why? [fish and chip or pizza]</p></li>
<li><p>Tonight is the night of genie! Yet another fellow Toastmaster has rescued a genie! This genie has a gift in languages and he can make you instantly fluent in either one of these three languages: Spanish, Italian or Russian. Which one will you choose and why? [Spanish, Italian or Russian]</p></li>
<li><p>We are on a roll! Another Toastmaster has saved a genie again! On no, guess what, it is the small business genie again! Apparently he keeps getting back into a bottle because of tax evasion! Again you can choose between these two choices: a new apple iphone every year or a new samsung galaxy every year. How would you choose? [Apple or Samsung]</p></li>
<li><p>Finally there is no more genie in a bottle to be found. However when you are walking on beach looking out for  a bottle, you run into this legendary Nigerian prince!  You gave him 50 bucks and he gave you back a princely sum of 20 million aussie right away. How are you going to spend the 20 million dollars?</p></li>
<li><p>We all know what is at the end of a rainbow! You are the lucky fellow who have reached the end of the rainbow and found the pot of gold! What will you do with the pot of gold?</p></li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Toastmaster speech 4]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/27/toastmaster-speech-4/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-27T07:06:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/27/toastmaster-speech-4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Feedback</h2>

<ul>
<li><p>The transition from introduction to first point can be done better</p></li>
<li><p>Hand clapping</p></li>
<li><p>Use of Jargon such as &lsquo;proxy&rsquo;</p></li>
<li><p>Repeated use of the word <code>Innovation</code></p></li>
<li><p>Subtitle can be improved</p></li>
</ul>


<h2>Self accessment</h2>

<p>Original version of the speech lasts almost 8 min. The final delivery time around 6m10s. A bit too fast.</p>

<p>I haven&rsquo;t been too successfully to use metaphors and vivid images in the speech. There is still use of jargon.</p>

<h1>Innovation</h1>

<p>Innovation has never got so much attention before. Innovation is a key driver of wealth creation. You probably already have an example of it in your pocket right now. Yes, nothing can highlight the impact of innovations better than Apple’s iPhone.</p>

<p>The success of iPhone actually combines several innovations in different area. They include supplier chain management, logistic, retails, brand management and product design.</p>

<p>So what it takes to be innovative? What can we do to come up with an truly innovative product? If you want to start the next Apple, the next Google or the next Tesla, You want to listen to these research results.</p>

<p>Size matters</p>

<p>Big corporate is not an ideal institute for innovation. Who would have thought? It is not so much a failure of the corporate because it is exactly what a corporate is designed for: avoid mistake! A big corporate has a series of command in place because new idea or product must be cross-examined and studied before they will receive a green light. They will do numerous marketing researches to decide if a product idea is viable.</p>

<p>When a product has to go through so many focus groups and polling, it is usually hardly innovative anymore. As Henry Ford has once put it famously: If you ask what a customer want out of a car, they will tell you a faster carriage!</p>

<p>That’s why over past decades, R&amp;D effort of giant like AT&amp;T, Xerox or IBM has little to show for as commercial products. Don’t get me wrong, their lab has produced brilliant ideas that change the world. For example Apple and Windows’ Graphical User Interface and Mouse is essentially a Xerox’s invention. But as an organisation, Xerox failed to capitalise the idea.</p>

<p>2) Gender matters</p>

<p>In another research, the researchers want to find out what makes a team great, or as they call it the Collective Intelligence. In two studies with about 700 people, working in groups of two to five, the researchers founds some factors that explains a group’s performance on a wide variety of tasks. This collective intelligence is not strongly correlated with the average or maximum individual intelligence of group members but is correlated with the average social sensitivity of group members and the equality in distribution of conversational turn-taking. And they are usually correlated to the proportion of females in the group.</p>

<p>In the tech startup world, teams are made up of usually predominantly socially awkward males (like me Exhibit A). Actually time and time again females have proven they are as competent if not better than their counterparts in engineering and computer science. If you are starting a new tech startup you should seriously rethink the prevailing bias against hiring females technical staff.</p>

<p>3) The mix matters</p>

<p>Have you thought about what a broadway musical successful? Is it the script or the score? Is it the genre? Is it the actors and actress? Or beautiful set and costume? After looking into how a company is formed, researchers find that actually it has a lot to do with the connections between the members: For a successful company, there is usually a healthy mix of, on the one hand, experienced veterans who have known and worked with each other for a long time, and on the other hand, relatively young and new members. Once this factor is identified, it just makes a lot of sense: The old and existing networks provides stability and experience to the team when the new kids on block comes and offer fresh angles and new inspiration. If the balance tilt either way, you will have either a company that may keep repeating its past success or a team of rookies who are struggling to get the basic right.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My toastmaster speech 3]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/21/my-toastmaster-speech-3/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-21T11:25:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/02/21/my-toastmaster-speech-3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Remark</h3>

<p>The original cut (as shown in following) is considerably longer than what I have delivered finally. It is because, after timing myself, the text takes about 8 min to finish. So I have trimmed off part of the speech. The paradox: when I finally delivered it in front of the audience, it took 9 seconds short of 6 minutes. I have talked a lot faster during the speech.</p>

<h3>Feedback</h3>

<ul>
<li><p>Vocal variation</p></li>
<li><p>The opening can be better</p></li>
<li><p>What I have done right: the speech provided a vivid imagery.</p></li>
</ul>


<h3>Text</h3>

<p>Memory. I want to talk to you about memory today.</p>

<p>I have watched a seminar by an American World Memory Championship champion Chester Santos just a month ago. I would love to share his insight and tip with you.</p>

<p>But before I continue, let’s me give you a little challenge. Let me give a list of random words and see if you can remember it. OK? Here it is:</p>

<p><strong>Monkey, Iron, Rope, Kite, House, Paper, Shoe, Worm, Envelope, Pencil, River, Rock, Tree, Coin</strong></p>

<p>Did you get them all? Do you think you can recite the list both forward and backward? I will tell you how later in the talk.</p>

<p>But first let me tell you about some common misunderstandings about memory.</p>

<p>The first common one is: our memory get worse when we get older. It is easy to understand why we have this misconception. When we were young and studying in schools, we have to remember tons of information and get quizzed from time to time. After we leave school and get our first job, we again need to absorb massive amount of new information in order to do our job well. However it is typical that in later stage of our lives, when we settle into our roles, we do not need to learn and recall the same amount of new information anymore. Since we do not use our brain for memorisation, its ability to retain and recall data becomes worse. It is just like any muscle system in our body: lack of exercise will make them weak. But we usually draw a wrong conclusion: we think our memory deteriorated because we are getting old. It is simply not true. It is more a result of our life style. As a good counter example, in a World Memory Championship some years ago, there was a contestant from Malaysia who is in his 60s. Despite his age, he managed to remember all entries in an oxford dictionary AND the words position on a page AND the associated page numbers.</p>

<p>Another misunderstanding is: it takes a special brain to memorise massive amount of data. Actually use of appropriate memory techniques will go a long way. Every one of us can master the techniques.</p>

<p>We have actually a lot of untapped memory capacity such as visual and olfactory memory. Visual memory is extremely powerful: for example, we can remember faces we have come across years ago. If we can enlist the visual memory, we can store a lot of information in our brain. The key is that the images have to be exaggerated, crazy and unusual.</p>

<p>It is very easy to understand why: lets say, out of nowhere, a big pink elephant break through those wall (points to far end), run across this room and then break this wall (points behind me) and escaped. I am sure 30 years from now, all of us will still recall every details of the episode and cannot stop talking about it.</p>

<p>Do you still remember the list I throw at you at the beginning of this speech? It is actually an example used by the World Memory Championship Champion Chester Santos in his demonstration. So let do this  visual memory exercise together!</p>

<p>First imagine a monkey who is happily running around and making some monkey sound. For some reason it finds a giant iron and he starts to dance around with the iron in his hand. On one end of iron it is attached to a rope. You can feel the rope and it feels rough. You look up the rope and you can see it is attached to a kite. Somehow the kite starts to fall and hit a house. The house is very special and is all covered by paper. Out of nowhere a  shoe appears and it walks on the papers and leave footprints all over the place.</p>

<p>Then you notice there is a worm in the shoe. Try picture this. You want to take a closer look but the worn jumps out and get inside an envelope. Now a pencil appears and write all over the envelope. The pencil then jumps into a river and makes a big splash. The river is crashing up a rock. Near the rock there is a tree. And there is cheese growing up on the tree. Coins are shooting out from the cheese.</p>

<p>Now you have a story. Now you have a picture. You can now easily recite the list of words: Monkey, Iron, Rope, Kite, House, Paper, Shoe, Worm, Envelope, Pencil, River, Rock, Tree, Coin. And you can go backward too. Do you try to it with me? Coin, Tree, Rock, River, Pencil, Envelope, Worm, Shoe, Paper, House, Kite, Rope, Iron, Monkey! Yes, you did it!</p>

<p>In conclusion: 1) Your memory does not get worse because you get old. It gets worse because you do not use it enough. 2) Our brain does not hold as much data as you wish because you do not know how to tape into your visual memory.</p>

<p>Thank You.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My attempt at toastmaster speech #2]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/01/13/toastmaster-speech-2/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-13T04:33:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ahwkong.com/post/2015/01/13/toastmaster-speech-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is my second speech and I find that writing a speech is not a easy task. First of all it takes time to think of a right topic. Then it takes a lot of practices and effort to be able to give the speech without note. It definitely motivated me to look at memorisation techniques.</p>

<h1>The Speech</h1>

<p>You are alone, in the dark. It is coming. It is getting closer. You can almost smell it. You are tired, you are exhausted. You are making a last ditch effort in last 12 hours non-stop. You are anxious because you are not sure if everything gonna turn out as planned. Your enemy is invisible yet its feels so real. I am talking about one of the worst enemies in our work lives: meeting the Deadline!</p>

<p>Does this feeling sound familiar to you? Raise your hand if you had this experience before!</p>

<p>Deadline is called deadline for good reasons. The time is set in stone. The consequence of failure is real. If your project misses the deadline, it could mean a failure to meet your customer expectation. Your organisation can suffer from reputational damage and some heads gonna roll! It could well be yours.</p>

<p>Can we tame this monster?</p>

<p>There is a few things you can do to make it easier to meet the deadlines</p>

<p>First of all, understand the objective of your project! It sounds obvious but it is extremely important.</p>

<p>Imagine you are an explorer and is lost in jungle. You want to get out of it alive. It really does not matter if you know how to clear a path with your machete or how to swing from tree to tree like Tarzan. But if you are heading the wrong direction you will never get out!</p>

<p>Sometimes we are too obsessed with operational details, we forget to ask the big picture question: What do we want to achieve? What is the expected outcome? How will we measure success or failure? These are the questions that we have to ask. These are the questions that set the direction.</p>

<p>Next. Planning. To plan well means we need to identify constraints and limitations we will face in a project.</p>

<p>A typical project has a lot of internal and external dependencies. These dependencies can become constraints and, in some case, even a blocker.</p>

<p>Here is a typical example of a constraint: The new system is dependent on the implementation of a new feature by an external vendor. The vendor does not have the capability to deliver this new feature in your timeframe. So our capability to deliver is constrained by how well the vendor can meet our deadline.</p>

<p>Sometimes a constraint can become a blocker. Say your project requires a key piece of new software which can only be run on an latest version of an operating system. But your internal IT insists that you can only use an older version because of policy.  How are you going to resolve it?</p>

<p>It is important to map out all the potential blockers on the critical path. The failure to do so can bring u unpleasant surprise.</p>

<p>3 Use milestones</p>

<p>Milestone is a technique to break a project down into smaller module. They are good checkpoints for monitoring the health of a project. Once you hit a milestone, it is a good time to pause and check if the original estimate is good, reexamine all the assumption, dependencies and constraints you have identified.</p>

<p>4 Set buffer.</p>

<p>What is buffer? Buffer basically means extra time and resources to prepare for the unexpected. Life is full of unexpected event. Your software vendor may suddenly goes of business; your key employee may become ill and cannot report to work for a while; A sudden change in market condition forces you make some last minute revision… All of these will add pressure on your already tight schedule. If you have not budgeted for these risks in a project, you will be likely end up in a position that you have to scramble to find extra resource and, more often than not, put extra pressure on an already stressed out team.</p>

<p>Burning midnight oil to meet deasline is not a fun experience. Keeping a good and even pace at work is key to avoid burnout. Therefore let me rehash the main points:</p>

<p>Understand the objective; know where you are going
Have a clear idea of the constraints and the limits &ndash; it can only done well if you understand your task or product well
Break a project into modules and assign milestones. Each milestone is a checkpoint to review the past performance and adjust the plan and direction.</p>

<p>With these technique you will be able to defeat this monster known as Deadline. After all we work to live, not live to work!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
