<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: book | Timeline]]></title>
  <link href="http://kongakong.github.io/blog/categories/book/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kongakong.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-23T17:25:36+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://kongakong.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Anthony Kong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA['Growing up Asian in Australia' by Alice Pung]]></title>
    <link href="http://kongakong.github.io/blog/2012/05/27/p-23853566417/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-27T19:29:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://kongakong.github.io/blog/2012/05/27/p-23853566417</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Another literary detour.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA['Shakespeare' by Bill Bryon]]></title>
    <link href="http://kongakong.github.io/blog/2012/05/13/p-22964166757/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-13T21:28:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://kongakong.github.io/blog/2012/05/13/p-22964166757</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While the book, Kafka’s The Trial, is still open, digitally nonetheless, I have taken a literary detour and finished the book “Shakespeare” by Bill Bryon.</p>

<p>Very interesting read.</p>

<p>There is not much known about William Shakespeare historically. There is simply not many documentation about him or his family. Despite this, Bill Bryon is still able to write a fascinating account of the time and era Shakespeare lived, in particular the often plague-ridden city, London, in around 1590 to 1620.</p>

<p>The reign of Elizabeth and James II, the swing between Protestantism and Catholicism in England, Gunpowder Plot happened in this period.</p>

<p>William Shakespeare died in 1616. Ming Dynasty ended in 1644. (They are totally irrelevant. I just like to compare what is happening on the other side of the world)</p>

<p>Actually it is rather interesting that while theatre and plays are all the rage in Shakespearean time, Chinese opera also reached its height in development in Ming dynasty. Since then the costume in Chinese opera are set in Ming era, despite the explicit ban of previous dynasty’s fashion by the Qing court.</p>

<p>Serious innovations in Chinese opera have to wait for another three hundred years to take place in colonial Hong Kong.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Start reading 'The Trial' by Kafka]]></title>
    <link href="http://kongakong.github.io/blog/2012/04/10/p-20787767752/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-10T03:56:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://kongakong.github.io/blog/2012/04/10/p-20787767752</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>To be precise, I actually <em>started</em> reading the book some ten years ago.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Start reading the book 'A World without Ice' by Henry Pollack]]></title>
    <link href="http://kongakong.github.io/blog/2012/03/14/p-19284625022/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-14T20:30:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://kongakong.github.io/blog/2012/03/14/p-19284625022</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="Start%20reading%20the%20book%20%22A%20World%20without%20Ice%22%20by%20Henry%20Pollack">http://www.worldwithoutice.com/</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA['Winston's War: Churchill, 1940-1945' by Max Hastings]]></title>
    <link href="http://kongakong.github.io/blog/2012/02/25/p-18208174417/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-25T09:00:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://kongakong.github.io/blog/2012/02/25/p-18208174417</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="None">http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/030726839X/</a></p>

<p>39% into the book and it is a fascinating read so far.</p>

<p>This book put a strong focus on the personality of Churchill and people around him (mainly his colleagues and his American counterparts) and interpersonal dynamics in and outside of the War Cabinet. It is a very refreshing angle.</p>

<p>Since I have read a few books on WWII before, the unfolding of events on the military front is not what I am after. In this regard this book is like a concise, light-weight refresher for me. Max has kept the military details to the minimum. To the contrary he spent a lot of time to talk about the reactions of Churchill, people in various important roles and general sentiment of the British populace to those events. The reactions and sentiment in turn shaped the future direction of war efforts and strategies.</p>

<p>What surprised me most is the passages about Franklin Roosevelt (FDR). He is described as smart, politically acute yet cautious and distant. No one around him can gauge his emotion or what is going on in his head. In some sense he is a very manipulative person. He cannot establish deep relationship with fellow humans.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
